<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>KK's Blog (Posts about NLP)</title><link>https://blog.fromkk.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://blog.fromkk.com/categories/nlp.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2018 &lt;a href="mailto:bebound gm@il.com"&gt;Kurt Lei&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 03:14:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Semi-supervised text classification using doc2vec and label spreading</title><link>https://blog.fromkk.com/posts/semi-supervised-text-classification-using-doc2vec-and-label-spreading/</link><dc:creator>Kurt Lei</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is a simple way to classify text without much human effort and get a impressive performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be divided into two steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get train data by using keyword classificaton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate a more accurate classification model by using doc2vec and label spreading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Keyword-based Classification&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keyword based classification is a simple but effective method. Extracting the target keyword is a monotonous work. I use this method to automatic extract keyword candicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find some most common words to classify the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use this equition to calculate the score of each word appears in the text.
   $$ score(i) = \frac{count(i)}{all\_count(i)^{0.3}}$$
   which $all\_count(i)$ is the word i's wordc ount in all corpus, and $count(i)$ is the word i's word count in positive corpus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the top words, add it to the final keyword list. Repeat this process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we can use the keywords to classify the text and get the train data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Classification by &lt;code&gt;doc2vec&lt;/code&gt; and Label Spreading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keyword-based classification sometimes produces the wrong result, as it can't using the symantic information in the text. Fortunately, Google has open sourced &lt;code&gt;word2vec&lt;/code&gt;, which can be used to produce semantically meaningful word embeddings. Furthermore, sentences can also be converted to vectors by using &lt;code&gt;doc2vec&lt;/code&gt;. Sentences which has closed meaning also have short vector distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the problem is how to classify these vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using corpus to train the &lt;code&gt;doc2vec&lt;/code&gt; model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;doc2vec&lt;/code&gt; model to convert sentence into vector.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using label spreading algorithm to train a classify model to classify the vectors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>doc2vec</category><category>mathjax</category><category>NLP</category><category>text classification</category><guid>https://blog.fromkk.com/posts/semi-supervised-text-classification-using-doc2vec-and-label-spreading/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 14:18:15 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>